hello today i will show and explain to
you
three different reports that affected
email confirmation functionality
on shopify shopify has a back bounty
program on hacker one
all the issues were reported by ron chan
also known as galock
and i think he's one of the best hunters
out there
getting a lot of five digits payouts he
also records
videos for youtube for channel recon
less i'd recommend it for you
because it's also short technical and
high quality
content so let's start with the first
report
and explain how was it possible to
confirm an
email you didn't have access to it was a
fairly easy process
let's say i have an email greg sunday at
we are hackerone.com and the email
i want to confirm is victim at
hackerone.com
so first i have to set up a trial
account
on shopify with the email that i control
so that would be
craigxandetweerhacker1.com
then before i confirmed my email
i changed it to victim at hackerone.com
then i have to wait a while and after a
few minutes
i have an email on my gregor sunday at
weirhackeron.com
with the email confirmation but happened
out
that when i click the confirm button i
actually confirm the other email that i
don't have access to
but the real question is what can we do
with it
because on most websites there is no
practical
attack scenario that would allow us to
exploit
such vulnerability but on shopify
if there are multiple accounts
registered with the same
confirmed email address it's possible to
connect those accounts
so if victim at hacker1com would have an
accounted shopify
i could now connect those accounts and
take over the victims
stores and their partner accounts
so that's a big impact but what's more
interesting
happened later so first
the shopify have deployed a temporary
fix and
gallop verified that it was okay it was
not bypassable
later they have marked the report as
resolved and deployed a permanent fix
this time he decided to test it again
and this time he succeeded
and what's more important here is that
he has not used
any trick to bypass it he's just done
the same thing
again and this time it worked happened
out that there actually were two
separate vulnerabilities
leading to the same impact as you've
seen on the timeline before
it was not possible to determine from
the attacker's perspective
whether the system has sent the email
before
or after you've changed the address
and the first fix only worked in a
situation
when the email verification was sent
before
the email address was chained by the
attacker and the separate root cause
made it possible to do the same thing
but
only in a situation when the attacker
would change the email address
before the verification email was sent
and what shopify did in this situation
was to
ask the hunter to submit a second report
and they have rewarded both of them
equally 15k
i think it's super cool from the shopify
team that they really
are transparent and honest because i
feel like most of the bug bounty
programs would just give you
one payout it really shows how they
really
really care about the relationship with
buck hunters
and 15k is a lot but it's only in the
middle
of the payout category for privileged
escalation to shop owner
and the question you might be asking
yourself is why wasn't it higher
and the reason is that it only affected
the accounts
that have not yet adopted a single login
system
and shopify team told that most of the
accounts
have adopted it so they were not
vulnerable
so keep that in mind because it will be
very important in a moment
the vulnerability only affected the
accounts
that have not adopted the single login
system
so now we can finally come to the third
vulnerability
it was submitted the same day that the
previous two were resolved
and this report was actually a way of
escalating
the previous two so it affected all the
users
and the interesting thing is that this
report
assumes that there is a way of
confirming someone's email address
but at the moment of writing this report
there was
not known way of doing this so this
report
was purely theoretical at the moment
i think it's worth pointing out because
probably
most hunters would not submit such a
report but also
most of the programs would likely reject
it
this vulnerability affected the flow of
connecting accounts
and the flow would look like this we
have two accounts with the same email
address
victim at hackeronecom one of the
accounts
is controlled by the attacker and one is
the real victim's account
then the attacker starts the process of
merging the two accounts
first he's prompted to submit
password to his store so this step is no
problem because
he knows this password but the next step
is problematic
because then the attacker has to put the
main shop's password and that's
something that the victim has set up
an attacker does not know it and that's
the reason
why the previous attack scenarios would
not work with the single login system
but in galock has found a way to bypass
this mechanism all he had to do
was to change the path from login to
account merge
new password and then he would have to
change the password to a new one
and did not have to put the old password
so this way he could submit the new
password
and actually take over the victim's
store
and account and the bounty for this
report
was 7.5 k with 5k being the
reward for escalating the previous
reports
and 2.5 k the reward for actually
this one which is half of minimum payout
for the buck in this category
because as i've said at the time of
reporting it was purely theoretical
so in total it was thirty seven thousand
five hundred dollars for the free
reports so that's it for today's video
as always i hope you have learned
something new as you can see i've
decided to
show my face so you know who's the guy
behind that voice
lately the channel has passed 1000
subscribers
i'm very grateful for that if you have
not subscribed yet
you can do it now also if you've enjoyed
the video
leave a like and for now goodbye